Guide to the Gorham Munson Papers on the American Social Credit Movement and New Democracy, 1899 - 1969, bulk 1932 - 1945
Gorham Munson Papers on the American Social Credit Movement and New Democracy, 1899 - 1969, bulk 1932 - 1945
- American Social Credit Movement Correspondence, 1938-1945
  - Parry, Albert, 1942 (3/2) (Box 12)
  - Paxson, W. L., 1938-1939 (4/4) (Box 12)
  - Pendill, Claudius G., 1939-1940 (3/4) (Box 12)
  - Pereira, Alvarez, 1939-1940 (6/5) (Box 12)
  - Por, Odon, 1938-1939 (3/2) (Box 12)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1940 (3/1) (Box 12)
  - Powell, G. F., 1939-1940 (10/9) (Box 12)
  - R - General, 1938-1943 (Box 13)
  - Ramsey, Chalres F., 1941-1942 (10/6) (Box 13)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1944 (4/0) (Box 13)
  - Rees, W. Arthur, 1939-1941 (8/4) (Box 13)
  - Robbins, H. M., 1939-1940 (2/4) (Box 13)
  - Rose, William, 1941-1943 (16/11) (Box 13)
  - Rosett, Blanche B., 1941-1942 (3/5) (Box 13)
  - Rowntree, Bernard, 1939, 1942-1943 (Box 13)
  - Ryden, C. W., 1938-1940 (2/2) (Box 13)
  - S - General, 1938-1942 (Box 13)
  - Schwarzenbach, Marguerite, 1938-1939 (1/4) (Box 13)
  - Scott, Evelyn, 1945 (1/0) (Box 13)
  - Seldes, Gilbert, 1939-1941 (1/1) (Box 13)
  - Shuttleworth, Frederick, 1940-1943 (9/9) (Box 13)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1944 (1/0) (Box 13)
  - Singer, Kurt, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Skorstad, J. B., 1939 (2/4) (Box 13)
  - Smith, Don Ingram, 1939 (2/2) (Box 13)
  - Solon, Israel, 1939-1942 (14/9) (Box 13)
  - Southam, William M., 1940-1943 (5/6) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1938 (4/2) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1939 (22/15) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1939 (15/18) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1940 (24/23) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1940 (19/8) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1941 (20/18) (Box 13)
  - Spencer, A. H., 1942-1945 (15/20) (Box 13)
  - Sweezy, Paul M., 1941 (1/3) (Box 13)
  - T - General, 1941-1943 (Box 13)
  - Tate, Allen, 1944 (1/0) (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Elliot, 1939, 1943-1944 (4/2) (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Harcourt M., 1938-1940 (6/3) (Box 13)
  - Thomason, O. M., 1942 (4/3) (Box 13)
  - Thompson, Richard Halliday, 1940-1941 (1/1) (Box 13)
  - Townsend, Sidney, 1941-1943 (3/2) (Box 13)
  - Travers, Pamela, 1941 (1/0) (Box 13)
  - Turner, R. R., 1938-1940 (2/4) (Box 13)
  - Van Dalsem, Newton, 1942 (3/5) (Box 14)
  - Vance, Yandray Wilson, 1941 (14/50) (Box 14)
  - Viens, E., 1939 (2/2) (Box 14)
  - Voorhis, Jerry F. (M. C.), 1941-1942 (37/29) (Box 14)
  - Voorhis, Jerry F. (M. C.), 1943-1945 (9/1) (Box 14)
  - W - General, 1938-1943 (Box 14)
  - Waldron, A. P., 1940 (3/3) (Box 14)
  - Watson, T. E. D., 1941 (4/1) (Box 14)
  - Watt, M., 1939 (3/3) (Box 14)
  - Welch, Mrs. E. Sohier, 1938-1943 (41/31) (Box 14)
  - Whiteman, L. H., 1938-1939 (2/2) (Box 14)
  - Wiley, Clarence, 1938-1943 (21/12) (Box 14)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1940 (4/5) (Box 14)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1941-1943 (4/5) (Box 14)
  - Willson, Corwin, 1940 (2/2) (Box 14)
  - Winchester, Harold P., 1938-1940 (9/8) (Box 14)
  - Wood, Richard R., 1939-1940 (9/8) (Box 14)
  - Woods, Vernon D., 1939 (2/2) (Box 14)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1940 (1/1) (Box 14)
  - Wyman, Albert L., 1938 (4/1) (Box 14)
  - X, Y, Z - General, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Zanettin, R. J., 1939-1942 (6/5) (Box 14)
  - Zigrosser, Carl, 1942 (3/2) (Box 14)
- Social Credit Subject File, 1932-1945
  Materials from a succession of Social Credit organizations in which Munson was engaged, publications with which he had business (including New Democracy), and individuals associated with him. The series is divided by country. Contents of folders vary and include correspondence, memoranda, mimeographed and printed material. A few items stemming from the 1920s are included.
  - Australia
    - Broadsheets and Pamphlets, 1936-1941 (Box 15, Folder 413)
  - Canada
    - Aberhart, William, Social Credit Manual, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 414)
    - Alberta Province - General, 1935-1939 (Box 15, Folder 415)
    - Beacon, The (Winnipeg), 1938-1940 (Box 15, Folder 416)
    - Douglas Social Credit Bureau of Canada (Ottawa), 1938-1940 (Box 15, Folder 417)
    - Douglas Social Credit Bureau of Canada (Toronto), 1933-1938 (Box 15, Folder 418)
    - Ligue du Credit Social de la Province de Quebec, La (Gardenville, P.Q.), 1938-1940 (Box 15, Folder 419)
    - Manitoba Social Credit Organization, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 420)
    - National Dividend Foundation of Canada (Vancouver, 1939-1941) (Box 15, Folder 421)
      See also William Rose.
    - National Social Credit Party of Canada (Vancouver), 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 422)
    - Today and Tomorrow (Edmonton), 1938-1942 (Box 15, Folder 423)
    - York Conference (York, Ontario) (Box 15, Folder 424)
    - York County Post (Scarboro Bluffs, Ontario), 1936 (Box 15, Folder 425)
    - Social Credit Association of Ontario, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 425A)
  - New Zealand
    - Douglas Social Credit Movement of New Zealand (Wellington) - correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 426)
    - Douglas Social Credit Movement of New Zealand (Wellington) - publications, 1938-1940 (Box 16, Folder 427)
    - Fortnightly Digest (Dunedin), 1935 (Box 16, Folder 428)
    - Lee, John Alexander - pamphlets, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 429)
    - New Zealand Social Credit Association (Hamilton) - publications, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 430)
  - United Kingdom
    - Chandos Group (London), 1935 (Box 16, Folder 431)
    - Douglas, Major C. H. - articles, speeches, 1925-1938 (Box 16, Folder 432)
    - Green Shirts, undated (Box 16, Folder 433)
    - Hargrave, John - correspondence, publications, 1935-1943 (Box 16, Folder 434)
    - Hargrave, John - typescript, They Can't Kill the Sun, undated (Box 16, Folder 435)
    - House of Commons, Social Credit Bill, Hearings, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 436)
    - Kibbo Kift, undated (Box 17, Folder 437)
    - Labor Party, Socialism and Social Credit, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 438)
    - The New Age (London), 1935-1940 (Box 17, Folder 439)
    - The New English Weekly (London)
      - Announcements, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 440)
      - Circulation in the United States, 1932-1933 (Box 17, Folder 441)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 442)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 443)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 444)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 17, Folder 445)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1938-1941 (Box 17, Folder 446)
      - Orage, A. R. - Supplement to New Democracy, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 447)
    - Norman, Montagu, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 448)
    - Orage, A. R., 1934 (Box 17, Folder 449)
    - Prosperity, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 450)
    - Public Welfare (London), 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 451)
    - Social Credit Co-ordinating Committee (Nottingham), 1939-1945 (Box 18, Folder 452)
    - Social Credit Party, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 453-454)
    - Social Credit Secretariat, Ltd., 1936-1940 (Box 18, Folder 455)
  - United States
    - American Social Credit Movement
      - Account Book No. 1, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 456)
      - Account Book No. 2, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 457)
      - Account Book No. 3, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 458)
      - Bulletins and Reports, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 459)
      - Bulletins and Reports, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 460)
      - Bulletins and Reports, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 461)
      - Bulletins and Reports, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 462)
      - Bulletins and Reports, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 463)
      - Central Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 464)
      - Finances, 1938-1942 (Box 19, Folder 465)
      - Financial Appeal, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 466)
      - Inventory, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 467)
      - Labor Committee, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 468)
      - Lists of Names, 1938-1942 (Box 20, Folder 469)
      - Membership Cards, 1938-1942 (Box 20, Folder 470)
      - Men First - Circulation, 1940-1943 (Box 20, Folder 471)
      - Men First - issues, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 472)
      - Men First - issues, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 473)
      - Men First - issues, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 474)
      - Men First - issues, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 475)
      - Press Releases, 1938-1942 (Box 20, Folder 476)
      - Publication Material, 1935-1940 (Box 20, Folder 477)
      - Technical Studies File, 1938-1939 (Box 20, Folder 478)
      - Treasurer's Communications, 1938-1942 (Box 20, Folder 479)
      - Unification Conference, September 1938 (Box 20, Folder 480)
      - Welch, Mrs. E. Sohier (Expulsion), 1939 (Box 20, Folder 481)
    - Black Sheep Club
      - Constitution, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 482)
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 483)
      - Members, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 484)
    - Boddy, Manchester, Views in the News
      - Columns, December 1934 (Box 21, Folder 485)
      - Columns, January-February 1935 (Box 21, Folder 486)
      - Columns, March-April 1935 (Box 21, Folder 487)
      - Columns, May-August 1935 (Box 21, Folder 488)
      - Columns, 1935-1936 (Box 21, Folder 489)
    - Buck, Howard L.
      - Broadsides, undated (Box 21, Folder 490)
      - Social Credit Columns, April-June 1935 (Box 21, Folder 491)
      - Social Credit Columns, July-September 1935 (Box 21, Folder 492)
      - Social Credit Columns, September-December 1935 (Box 21, Folder 493)
    - Committee in Support of H.R. 7188 - Legislation
      - Bills Introduced, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 494)
      - Bills Introduced, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 495)
      - Bills Introduced, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 496)
      - Bills Introduced, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 497)
      - Bills Introduced, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 498)
      - Bills Introduced, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 499)
      - Bills Introduced, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 500)
      - Hearings, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 501)
      - Hearings, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 502)
      - Remarks of Charles G. Binderup (M.C.), 1937 (Box 22, Folder 503)
      - Remarks of Fred L. Crawford (M.C.), 1939 (Box 22, Folder 504)
      - Remarks of Alan T. Goldsborough (M.C.), 1935-1939 (Box 22, Folder 505)
      - Remarks of Jerry F. Voorhis (M.C.), 1937-1942 (Box 22, Folder 506)
    - Committee in Support of H.R. 7188 - Lobbying
      - Appeals, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 507)
      - Bills drafted, 1935-1940 (Box 22, Folder 508)
      - Congressmen - Interviews, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 509)
      - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 510)
      - Expenses, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 511)
      - Goldsborough, Alan T. (M.C.), 1938 (Box 22, Folder 512)
      - Gwathmey, T. Allan, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 513)
      - Haight, Raymond L., 1938 (Box 22, Folder 514)
      - Hampden, Paul, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 515)
      - Harvey, Edward F., 1938 (Box 23, Folder 516)
      - Hearings, Report of Gorham Munson on, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 517)
      - Larkin, J. Crate, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 518)
      - Memoranda, 1936-1938 (Box 23, Folder 519)
      - Records, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 520)
      - Voorhis, Jerry F. (M.C.), 1938-1940 (Box 23, Folder 521)
    - Coward, Vanessa. Coward-McCann, Inc., 1933-1940 (Box 23, Folder 522)
    - Demand Consumer Credit Campaign (Detroit), 1940 (Box 23, Folder 523)
    - Free America, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 524)
    - Gwathmey, T. Allan, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 525)
    - Hansen, Alvin E., Social Credit Proposals, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 526)
    - Honest Money Founders, Inc. (Chicago), 1939 (Box 23, Folder 527)
    - Larkin, J. Crate, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 528)
    - League for National Dividends (San Francisco), 1938 (Box 23, Folder 529)
    - Mack, Harold L., 1936 (Box 24, Folder 530)
    - Midwest Monetary Foundation (Chicago), 1941 (Box 24, Folder 531)
    - Money, undated (Box 24, Folder 532)
    - National Social Credit Association (New York City)
      - Bulletins, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 533)
      - Bulletins, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 534)
      - Bulletins, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 535)
    - National Workers League (Detroit), 1938 (Box 24, Folder 536)
    - New Democracy
      - Advertising, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 537)
      - Articles, published and unpublished, 1933-1937 (Box 24, Folder 538)
      - Bulletins, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 539)
      - Business, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 540)
      - Circulation, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 541)
      - Financial Support, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 542)
      - Incorporation, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 543)
      - Policy and Reports, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 544)
      - Promotional Material, 1933-1936 (Box 24, Folder 545)
      - Stock Subscription Offer, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 546)
    - New Economics Group of New York
      - Broadsheets, undated (Box 25, Folder 547)
      - Bulletins and Circulars, February-July, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 548)
      - Bulletins and Circulars, July-August 1933 (Box 25, Folder 549)
      - Bulletins and Circulars, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 550)
      - Bulletins and Circulars, 1936 (Box 25, Folder 551-552)
      - Goldsborough Bill Documents, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 553)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 554)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 555)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1936 (Box 25, Folder 556)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 557)
      - Munson, Gorham - correspondence, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 558)
      - Pamphlets, undated (Box 25, Folder 559)
    - New Era, 1938 (Box 25, Folder 560)
    - New Leader, The, 1938-1942 (Box 25, Folder 561)
    - New Republic, The, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 562)
    - Pacific Coast Social Credit Federation, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 563)
    - Peekskill Daily Union (Peekskill, New York), 1935 (Box 26, Folder 564)
    - Poetry, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 565)
    - River, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 566)
    - Ryder, Warren David, undated (Box 26, Folder 567)
    - Social Credit Bulletin Board, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 568)
    - Social Credit Group of Detroit, undated (Box 26, Folder 569)
    - Social Credit Party (Detroit), 1935 (Box 26, Folder 570)
    - Social Credit Illustrated, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 571)
    - Taliesin Square Paper, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 572)
    - University of Virginia, Institute of Public Affairs: Charlottesville Conference on Social Credit, July 10-11, 1936
      - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 573)
      - Hampden, Paul, The Flaw in the Price System, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 574)
      - Hampden, Walter, The Professions and the Money Question, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 575)
      - Harvey, Edward F., Financing a Power Economy, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 576)
      - Laughlin, James, IV, The Artist, the Audience, and Social Credit, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 577)
      - Munson, Gorham, Social Credit and Political Action, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 578)
      - Williams, William Carlos, The Attack on Credit Monopoly from a Cultural Viewpoint, 1936 (Box 26, Folder 579)
- Munson Correspondence, 1922-1964
  Scattered exchanges chiefly on topics other than Social Credit arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Anderson, Margaret, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 580)
  - Bishop, Morris, 1959 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 581)
  - Brickell, Hershel, 1949 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 582)
  - Burke, Kenneth, 1948 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 583)
  - Cane, Melville, 1943-1956 (8/0) (Box 27, Folder 584)
  - Clyma, Cecil, 1963 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 585)
  - Crichton, Kyle, 1949 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 586)
  - Daniel, Harry, 1963 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 587)
  - Emerson, R. W., 1948 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 588)
  - Evans, A. H., 1960 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 589)
  - Ferril, T. H., 1950 (2/2) (Box 27, Folder 590)
  - Fiene, Ernest, 1949 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 591)
  - Flesch, Rudolph, 1948-1949 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 592)
  - Foerster, Norman, 1958 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 593)
  - Frank, Waldo, 1947-1963 (7/2) (Box 27, Folder 594)
  - Frost, Robert, 1961 (1/1) (Box 27, Folder 595)
  - Hampden, Paul, 1963 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 596)
  - Hargrave, John, 1946 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 597)
  - Harolde, Mary (Mrs. Ralph), 1965 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 598)
  - Janney, Russell, 1946-1957 (4/0) (Box 27, Folder 599)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1948 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 600)
  - Johnson, Dallas, undated (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 601)
  - Johnstone, Forrester, 1946 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 602)
  - Jones, Idwal, 1948-1949 (3/0) (Box 27, Folder 603)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1957 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 604)
  - Larsson, Raymond E. F., 1952-1954 (4/0) (Box 27, Folder 605)
  - Laughlin, James IV, 1960 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 606)
  - McHugh, Vincent, 1950-1953 (3/0) (Box 27, Folder 607)
  - Munson - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 608)
  - Orage, Jessie, 1946 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 609)
  - Regnery, Henry, 1964 (1/0) (Box 27, Folder 610)
  - Reid, Ralph, 1962 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 611)
  - Riggs, I., 1964 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 612)
  - Snow, Wilbert, 1961-1962 (3/0) (Box 27, Folder 613)
  - Thirlwall, John C., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 614)
  - Thompson, Robert N. (M.P.), 1962-1963 (2/0) (Box 27, Folder 615)
  - Toomer, Jean, 1922-1923 (9/25) (Box 27, Folder 616)
    Copies of the originals which Munson had previously given to Fisk University.
  - Toomer, Jean, 1924 (3/8) (Box 27, Folder 617)
  - Toomer, Jean, 1927-1932 (2/17) (Box 27, Folder 618)
  - Toomer, Jean, 1940-1947 (9/4) (Box 27, Folder 619)
- Munson Writings, 1923-1963
  Reviews of some of Munson's books. Copies of magazines in which his articles appeared and some tearsheets of his articles; the arrangement is alphabetical by title of the magazines. Manuscripts and typescripts, published and unpublished, are grouped roughly by period. Biographical information and photographs of Munson.
  - Books
    - Waldo Frank. Robert Frost. Destinations. Reviews, 1923, 1924, 1927. (Box 28, Folder 620)
    - Twelve Decisive Battles of the Mind. Reviews, 1942. (Box 28, Folder 621)
    - Aladdin's Lamp. Correspondence, 1945. (Box 28, Folder 622)
    - Aladdin's Lamp. Reviews, 1945. (Box 28, Folder 623)
    - Written Word, The. Reviews. (Box 28, Folder 624)
  - Articles
    - List of Articles published by Gorham Munson (Box 28, Folder 625)
    - American Mercury, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 626)
    - Ancient Wisdom, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 627)
    - Antioch Review, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 628)
    - Background, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 629)
    - Christian Century, 1935, 1938, 1939, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 630)
    - Commonweal, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 631)
    - Contempo: A Review of Books and Personalities, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 632)
    - Dynamic America, 1938-1942 (Box 28, Folder 633-636)
    - Lewiston Journal, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 637)
    - Modern Quarterly, 1938, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 638)
    - New English Weekly, 1933-1939 (Box 29, Folder 639-645)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 646)
    - Opinion: A Journal of Jewish Life and Letters, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 647)
    - Order: A quarterly of American Integration, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 648)
    - People's Money, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 649)
    - River: A Magazine of the Deep South, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 650)
    - Scholastic: The National High School Weekly, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 651)
    - Security, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 652)
    - Social Frontier, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 653)
    - Tomorrow, 1943-1946, 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 654-657)
    - University Review, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 658)
    - Village Echo, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 659)
    - World Unity, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 660)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 30, Folder 661-668)
  - Biographical Materials
    - Autobiographical notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 669)
    - Biographical items, undated (Box 30, Folder 670)
    - Photographs of Gorham Munson (Box 30, Folder 671)
      - In Woodstock, New York, 1920
      - By Man Ray, 1920
      - From a painting by Ernest Fiene, 1926
      - At typewriter in ASCM office, circa 1940
      - With books, circa 1945
      - By Robert Daseler in Middletown, Connecticut, 1969
- Pamphlets
  101 pamphlets dealing chiefly with Social Credit.
  - Adams, James Truslow. What Next in America? n.p., 1928? 16 pp. (Box 31-33)
  - American National Dividend League. One Hundred Dollars: What the Banks Have Done to Us and What We Can Do for Ourselves. Los Angeles 1939.
  - Angas, Lawrence Lee Bazley. The Coming Collapse in Gold. London: St. Clements Press, 1933. 91 pp.
  - Barclay-Smith, Colin. Dividends for All! Sydney: Commercial Printing Co., 1935? 40 pp.
  - Barclay-Smith, Colin. The Miracle of the Machine. Sydney: Commercial Printing Co., 1935? 40 pp.
  - Barclay-Smith, Colin. Victory Without Debt. Sydney: Leisure Hour Publishing Co., 1940. 93 pp.
  - Brenton, Arthur. The Veil of Finance. London: Credit Research Library, 1933? 64 pp.
  - British Columbia Social Credit League. What Does Social Credit Propose to Do? Manifesto 1936. Vancouver, 1936. 20 pp.
  - Burbidge, Dighton W. Fancies and Delusions Concerning the Douglas Social Credit Proposals, a Reply to Professor D. B. Copland. Melbourne: J. W. Knapton & Co., 1932. 35 pp.
  - Burdick, Usher Lloyd. How the Federal Reserve Brought on Depression and Ruined the Entire Country. Bismarck, N.D.: Bismarck Printing Co., 1934. 24 pp.
  - Byrne, L. D. Alternative to Disaster, the Case for Social Credit. London: Social Credit Secretariat, 1938? 31 pp.
  - California Attorneys Committee for Payroll Guarantee Amendment. The First Step to Prevent Post-War Depression. San Francisco, 1942. 16 pp.
  - Carter, Margaret. When the Devil Drives, a Comedy in Three Acts. Leicester, England: Blackfriars Press, 1936. 80 pp.
  - Cole, George Douglas Howard. Fifty Propositions About Money and Production. London: Stanley Nott; 1936. 32 pp.
  - Corke, Helen. From Scarcity to Plenty: A Short Course in Economic History from the XVIIth Century to the Present Day. London: Stanley Nott, 1935? 31 pp.
  - Credit Study Group. Questions and Answers Upon Social Credit. Originally published under the heading Question Time in the New English Weekly. London? 1934?
  - Cumberland, Marten, and Harrison, Raymond. The New Economics. 2d ed. London: Stanley Nott, 1936. 119 pp.
  - D., R. S. Demand and Supply, Money and Prices Under Social Credit. n.p., 1936. 53 pp.
  - D., R. S. Necessity for Effectual Economic Demand. New York?: American Social Credit Movement, 1940. 68 pp. 2 copies.
  - Deane, Albert Lytle. The Deane Plan. Presentation by Albert Lytle Deane and Henry Kittredge Norton. New York?, June 1933. 60 pp.
  - Dee, Elles. Economics for Everybody, or the Intelligent Enquirer's Guide to Wisdom. 2d ed. London: Printed for the author by Wightman & Co., 1935. 43 pp.
  - Dodds, Gilbert W. This is Social Credit: A Comprehensive Explanation of Social Credit Policies and Principles as They Would Apply to the Economy of New Zealand. Wellington: Social credit Promoters, 1957. 50 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Douglas Theory, a Reply to Mr. J. A. Hobson. London: Cecil Palmer, 1922. 9 pp. 2 copies.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Nature of Democracy. New York: New Economics Group, 1934. 16 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The New and the Old Economics, a Reply to Professor D. B. Copland and Professor Lionel Robbins. Edinburgh: Scots Free Press, 1936? 36 pp. 2 copies.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Programme for the Third World War. Liverpool: K. R. P. Publications, 1943? 60 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Tragedy of Human Effort. London: Social Credit Secretariat, 1936. 19 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. These Present Discontents and the Labour Party and Social Credit. London: Cecil Palmer, 1922. 44 pp.
  - Douglas Social Credit Movement (Belfast Group). Social Credit Restated, a Rejoinder to Rev. Prof. Corkey. Belfast, 1936. 31 pp.
  - Drinkwater, Frances Harold. Seven Addresses on Social Justice. London: Burns, Oates & Washbourne, 1937. 99 pp.
  - Even, Louis. Pourquoi Taxer?... Montreal: Institut d'action politique, 1953. 47 pp.
  - Farland, pseud. National Debt... or National Dividend? Winnipeg: F. A. Ireland, 194-. 16 pp. 2 copies.
  - Farland, pseud. This is Yours. Winnipeg?, 1937? 31 pp.
  - Fifty Years of Social Credit, 1919-1969: C. H. Douglas. Mexborough, Yorks: Social Credit Co-ordinating Centre, 1969. 64 pp.